# **Maxwell Riesel**

Schenectady, NY 12304 | (315)-868-6284 | maxwellriesel1998@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

## **Summary**

Computer analyst and programmer with successful experience in fast paced office settings and factory floors. Team member and independent worker with skills ranging from hardware maintenance and repair to software design and implementation. Organized, punctual professional who cares for great documentation. Prepared to begin a role in a dedicated development environment.

# Qualifications

- Able to program, maintain, and administer clean code for efficient programming.
- Manage and create proper documentation for individual functions and applications as a whole.
- Perfection of soft skills and communication through all previous work experiences.

### **Professional Skills**

# Languages, Frameworks, RTEs and other tools

- Proficiency of 3 years or more in C++, C#, Java, Python, Javascript, Typescript, CSS, and HTML.
- Proficiency in React, ASP.Net, Angular, Bootstrap, Express.js, and Jquery.
- Utilized notable RTEs Java Virtual Machine, .Net environment, and NodeJs.
- Utilization and proficiency in Amazon Web services, including serverless web apps.

#### Soft Skills

- Management of service to client relations.
- Experience communicating goals and procedures to other non technical teams.
- Experience in customer service, including follow-ups, general inquiries, and problem solving.
- Experience communicating with users and clients of differing cultural backgrounds.
- Proficiency in Spanish.

### Documentation and testing

- Usage of ticketing and knowledge base software to create and manage detail oriented documentation
- Creation of outline focused documentation for applications greater than 40,000 lines
- Experience performing unit testing to ensure high quality of code

# **Work History**

**IT Analyst** Dec 2023-Current **CDPHP** Albany, NY Web Developer Jan 2022-Current Baron Insurance & Tax Agency Remote **Printer Technician** Feb 2023-Dec 2023 **US Globe Corp** East Greenbush NY **Onsite Technician** Aug 2022-Feb 2023 Hemmersbach Albany NY **Software Engineer** Jan 2022-Aug 2022 Herkimer County Information Services Herkimer NY IT Technician June 2021-Jan 2022 Turbo Machined Products. Frankfort NY **Produce Associate** Sep 2017-June 2021

## Education

Hannafords

Bachelor of Science: **Computer Information Science**SUNY Polytechnic Institute

Dec 2021

Utica NY

Herkimer NY

# Certifications

- FullStack development bootcamp Certification of completion
- Angela Yu Web Development bootcamp Certificate of Completion
- Hackerrank Python(basic) Certification